Guide to the Herbert Aptheker Papers, 1842-1999, (bulk 1934-1994)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Aptheker Articles, Manuscripts, and Notes
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Truman lied to excuse the inexcusable. -- In People's Daily World, 1986 June 5 (Box 116, Folder 43)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Pope John Paul rejects dialogue with Marxism, 1986 June 19 (Box 116, Folder 44)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reagan's war on Libya: causes & cure. -- p. 5-9. -- In Political Affairs, 1986 June (Box 116, Folder 45)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Guatemala then, Nicaragua now? -- p. 9-A. -- In People's Daily World, 1986 July 8 (Box 116, Folder 46)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Anti-Nazi hero recognized by the State of Wisconsin. -- In Daily World, 1986 July 22 (Box 116, Folder 47)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Mass illiteracy in the U.S. and how to wipe it out, 1986 July 25, tms (3 p.) (Box 116, Folder 48)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. To save humanity. -- p. 2. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1986 July / Aug. (Box 116, Folder 49)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reagan won't spend to fight mass illiteracy, 1986 Aug. 9 (Box 116, Folder 50)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. What is Meese investigating?, 1986 Aug. 20 (Box 116, Folder 51)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Will Nicaragua be Reagan's Vietnam?, 1986 Sept. 3 (Box 116, Folder 52)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Memoir of trip to NYC, 1986 Sept. 19, ams (1 p.) (Box 116, Folder 53)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Black and red: W.E.B. Du Bois ... by Gerald Home. -- In Journal of American History, 1986 Sept. (Box 116, Folder 54)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reagan: Goebbels like liar and Israel's ally. -- p. 12-14. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1986 Sept./ Oct., 2 copies (Box 116, Folder 55)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. S. & S.: some memories. -- In Science & Society. -- Vol. 50, no. 3, 1986 Fall (Box 116, Folder 56)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of John Hope Franklin's George Washington Williams: a biography. -- p. 1004-1005. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 91, 1986 Oct. (Box 116, Folder 57)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, Radical History, 1986 Nov. 18, tms (1 p.) + clipping (Box 116, Folder 58)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The myth of the Soviet military threat, 1986 Nov. 18, tms (4 p.) (Box 116, Folder 59)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The media buys another lie about the Soviet Union, 1986 Nov. 21 (Box 116, Folder 60)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. German big business and the rise of Hitlerism, 1986, tms (26 p.) + tms (33 p.) (Box 116, Folder 61)
  - Transcription of lectures: FDR to Reagan: Marxist Studies Series, Berkeley, Calif., 1986 (Box 116, Folder 62)
  - Aptheker bibliography, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Flyers, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous [1 of 2], 1986 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous [2 of 2], 1986 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986 - 1987 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence with Bettina Aptheker from 1986.
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The constitution and Afro-American people, 1987 Jan., ams (5 p.) (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. U.C. Santa Barbara presentation on W.E.B. Du Bois: lecture notes, 1987 Feb. 2, ams (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The constitution and the Afro-American people. -- In People's Daily World, 1987 Feb. 19 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Lying to prevent disarmament, 1987 Feb. 20 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor on Jews in the Soviet Union, 1987 Mar. 3, ams (1 l.) (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the Iran Contra affair, 1987 Mar. 5, tms (3 p.) + clipping (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor re: Rabbi Frankel, 1987 Mar. 26 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Irangate, Reagan - and Israel. -- p. 2, 1987 Mar. / Apr. (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The Times is amazed, again, 1987 Apr. 17 (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On affirmative action, the Civil Rights Movement, and the Reagan administration, 1987 Apr. 21, tms (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 16)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On Trotsky: comment on Reed and Jakobsen article in the American Historical Review, 1987 Apr., ams (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 17)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reagan launches a counter-revolution, 1987 May 7 (Box 117, Folder 18)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. U.S. and Soviet lawyers discuss peace & justice, 1987 May 21 (Box 117, Folder 19)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Jefferson's ghost must be squirming, 1987 May 25 (Box 117, Folder 20)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The constitution and slavery. -- p. 2-4. -- In Jewish Affairs. -- Vol. 17, no. 2, 1987 May / June (Box 117, Folder 21)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. New papers reveal more about Trotsky, 1987 June 3 (Box 117, Folder 22)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On Jews in the Soviet Union, 1987 June 5, ams (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 23)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. 'A gathering of ultra-wing fanatics': on understanding the Times, 1987 June 8, ams (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 24)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Ultra-right fanatics set for comeback. -- In People's Daily World, 1987 June 17 (Box 117, Folder 25)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Questions the reported numbers of Soviet Jews who seek to emigrate. -- In The Sentinel, 1987 June 18 (Box 117, Folder 26)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Comments on James Axtell's Europeans, Indians, and the age of discovery in American history textbooks. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 92, 1987 June, ams (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 27)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of New perspectives on race and slavery in America, ed. by Robert H. Abzug and Stephen E. Maizlish. -- p. 102-103. -- In Florida Historical Quarterly, 1987 Summer (Box 117, Folder 28)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Comment on Ted Koppel's TV show on General Bernard Rogers, 1987 July 1, ams (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 29)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Education in the U.S. is in crisis, 1987 July 3 (Box 117, Folder 30)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Schultz touches a nerve, 1987 July 28, ams (3 p.) (Box 117, Folder 31)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Schultz, Reagan, and the fascist four, 1987 July 31 (Box 117, Folder 32)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Schultz makes a point, but a demagogic one, 1987 Aug. 6 (Box 117, Folder 33)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. North America's first inhabitants & U.S. textbooks, 1987 Aug. 11 (Box 117, Folder 34)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, New York Times, on Iran-Contras, 1987 Aug. 17, ams (3 p.) + clipping (Box 117, Folder 35)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, New York Times, on South Africa and Contras, 1987 Aug. 24, ams (3 p.) + clippings (Box 117, Folder 36)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Much more than a sigh is needed, 1987 Aug. 29 (Box 117, Folder 37)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Proposed volume from introductions to Collected published writings of W.E.B. Du Bois, 1987 Sept. 14, tmss (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 38)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Racism kills: then and now, 1987 Sept. 15 (Box 117, Folder 39)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. 'Solidarity', Reagan, and the Contras, 1987 Sept. 22, tms (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 40)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, Christian Century, re: Glen Hewitt's Victimized by justice, 1987 Sept. 28, tms (2 p.) + clippings (Box 117, Folder 41)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The U.S. Constitution and Reaganism. -- p. 5-8. -- In Jewish Affairs. -- Vol. 17, no. 5, 1987 Sept. / Oct. (Box 117, Folder 42)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. President Joe McCarthy, 1987 Oct. 2, tms (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 43)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. 'Solidarity', Reagan, and the Contras, 1987 Oct. 2 (Box 117, Folder 44)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The U.S. constitution and Reaganism, 1987 Oct. 4, amss (12 p.) (Box 117, Folder 45)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. President Joe McCarthy, 1987 Oct. 13 (Box 117, Folder 46)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor re: Glen Hewitt's Victimized by justice. -- In Christian Century, 1987 Oct. 28 (Box 117, Folder 47)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Remarks in L.A. (First Unitarian Church) Solidarity with Judah Party - 46th anniversary, 1987 Nov. 21, ams (8 p.) (Box 117, Folder 48)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, the New York Times, on American negro slave revolts, 1987 Nov. 24, tms (2 p.) (Box 117, Folder 49)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Anti-racism in the U.S.: an introduction. -- In SAGE Race Relations Abstracts. -- Vol. 12, no. 4, 1987 Nov., 2 copies (Box 117, Folder 50)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Perjury and torture as state policy, 1987 Dec. 6, tms (2 p.) + ams (7 p.) + clippings (Box 117, Folder 51)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Perjury and torture as state policy, 1987 Dec. 15 (Box 117, Folder 52)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Corrections to ms on abolitionism & correspondence with Athenaide Dallett, 1987 Dec. (Box 117, Folder 53)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On prosecution of Nazi war criminals, [1987], ams (1 l.) (Box 117, Folder 54)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the constitution, 1987, tms (26 p.) (Box 117, Folder 55)
  - Articles and letters by Herbert Aptheker, 1987 (Box 117, Folder 56)
  - Flyers, 1987 (Box 117, Folder 57)
  - Notes to self, 1987 (Box 117, Folder 58)
  - Lecture notes, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - 50th anniversary of Negro Slave revolts, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - U.C. Berkeley Marxist Studies Series. Dr. Herbert Aptheker: from the New Deal to Reaganism: recommended readings, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - U.C. Berkeley Marxist Studies Series, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of appreciation to Herbert Aptheker for serving as a judge in the National Bicentennial Writing Competition, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The rebellion of the Palestinian people, 1988 Jan. 2 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. A chilling wave of racism. -- p. 9-A. -- In People's Daily World, 1988 Jan. 30 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. For a nuclear-free globe, 1988 Feb. 2 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The slave revolts. -- In New York Review, 1988 Mar. 3 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Early works on unionism hold message for today, 1988 Mar. 19 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Three torchbearers of freedom, 1988 Mar. 25 (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Action is urged to abolish Ky. women's prison unit, 1988 Apr. 15 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Virulent anti-communism in idealistic socialist vision, 1988 Apr. 30 (Box 118, Folder 15)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The Israeli problem and a solution. -- p. 9-A. -- In People's Daily World, 1988 May 13 (Box 118, Folder 16)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Affirmative action: what it is and is not, 1988 May 27 (Box 118, Folder 17)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The birth of Israel. -- p. 14-15. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1988 May - June (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The Jackson candidacy, 1988 June 10 (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Masterwork on racism pays tribute to Du Bois, 1988 June 11 (Box 118, Folder 20)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. An American. -- In People's Daily World, 1988 June 18 (Box 118, Folder 21)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Charles W. Boyd's Your legacy from Thaddeus Stevens, 1988 June 27, tms (2 p.) + clipping (Box 118, Folder 22)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Excusing an informer, 1988 July 8 (Box 118, Folder 23)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Imperialism's criminality, 1988 July 22 (Box 118, Folder 24)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Imperialism's criminality, ca. 1988 July, tms (2 p.) (Box 118, Folder 25)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Peace in the mid-East: seize the moment. -- p. 2. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1988 July - Aug. (Box 118, Folder 26)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Reunion: a memoir by Tom Hayden, 1988 Aug. 6 (Box 118, Folder 27)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Reunion: a memoir by Tom Hayden, 1988 Aug. 6 (Box 118, Folder 28)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the Wright-Buroway exchange, 1988 Aug. 9, tms (7 p.) (Box 118, Folder 29)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Capitalism, communism & coexistence: Galbraith, Menshikov on 'learning to live together', 1988 Aug. 13 (Box 118, Folder 30)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The U.S. and direct broadcast satellite: United States imperialism via electronics, 1988 Aug. 27 (Box 118, Folder 31)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reconstruction: a monumental new study. -- p. 33-36. -- In Political Affairs, 1988 Aug. (Box 118, Folder 32)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Blow back by Christopher Simpson, 1988 Sept. 9 (Box 118, Folder 33)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Academic freedom and the CIA, 1988 Sept. 23 (Box 118, Folder 34)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Jews and the 1988 presidential election. -- New York: Jewish Affairs,, 1988 Oct. 2 (Box 118, Folder 35)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Is Jim Crow to return?, 1988 Oct. 28 (Box 118, Folder 36)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Glorifying fascism, 1988 Nov. 25 (Box 118, Folder 37)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Valuable, inspiring study of Populist's pro-labor role, 1988 Nov. 30 (Box 118, Folder 38)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the 71st anniversary of the great October revolution. -- p. 5-6., 1988 Nov. / Dec. (Box 118, Folder 39)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The election of 1986. -- p. 3. -- In Political Affairs, 1988 Nov. / Dec. (Box 118, Folder 40)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reaction and racism. -- In People's Daily World, 1988 Dec. 9 (Box 118, Folder 41)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. 200 years of USA constitution. -- p. 183-196. -- In GDR Committee for Human Rights bulletin. -- No. 3, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 42)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the Wright / Buroway exchange. -- p. 107-110. -- In Berkeley Journal of Sociology, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 43)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the bicentennial of the Constitution: a Marxist view. -- p. 277-290. -- In Nature, Society, and Thought. -- Vol. 1, no. 2, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 44)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of No ivory tower: McCarthyism and the universities by Ellen Schrecker. -- p. 1094-[1095]. -- In Journal of American History. -- Vol. 74, no. 3, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 45)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Zweihundert Jahre USA-Verfassung. -- p. 183-198. -- IN Schriften und Informationen, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 46)
  - Flyers, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 47)
  - Lecture notes, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 49)
  - Marxist Study Series, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 50)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 118, Folder 52)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Slaveowner's own words bare racism's economic base. -- In People's Daily World, 1989 Jan. 10 (Box 118, Folder 53)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Parenti spotlights devastating foreign policy of U.S. -- p. 11-A. -- In People's Daily World, 1989 Jan. 31 (Box 118, Folder 54)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. To make the world anew: Gorbachev's UN address. -- p. 4-5. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1989 Jan. / Feb. (Box 118, Folder 55)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Racism and reaction, 1989 Feb. 9 (Box 118, Folder 56)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Pinochet, 1989 Mar. 6 (Box 118, Folder 57)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Elizabeth Fox-Genovese's Within the plantation household. -- p. 44-45. -- In Political Affairs, 1989 Mar. (Box 118, Folder 58)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Racism and free speech. -- p. 5-6. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1989 Mar. / Apr. (Box 118, Folder 59)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reviews of Arno J. Mayer's Why did the heaven's not darken? -- p. 14-15, 20. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1989 May / June (Box 118, Folder 60)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the bicentennial of the French Revolution. -- p. 10-12. -- In Political Affairs, 1989 July (Box 118, Folder 61)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The Reagan-Bush Supreme Court and human rights. -- p. 5,24. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1989 July / Aug. - Sept. / Oct. (Box 118, Folder 62)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Soviet's analysis needs some amendments, 1989 Sept. 8 (Box 118, Folder 63)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Welcoming Jonathan Wiener's paper, with a few dissents. -- Reprinted from The Journal of American History. -- Vol. 76, no. 2, 1989 Sept. (Box 118, Folder 64)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Review of Everything is changing by David DeLeon. -- p. 651. -- In Journal of American History. -- Vol. 76, no. 2, 1989 Sept. (Box 118, Folder 65)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. For a socialist United States, 1989 Oct. 5 (Box 118, Folder 66)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the 70th anniversary of the Communisty Party, U.S.A. -- p. 5-6. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1989 Nov. / Dec. (Box 118, Folder 67)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Religion and Marxism. -- p. 15. -- In People's Daily World, 1989 Dec. 28 (Box 118, Folder 68)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Marxism: demise or renewal? -- p. 5-9. -- In Political Affairs, 1989 Dec. (Box 118, Folder 69)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On the Wright / Burawoy exchange. -- p. 107-110. -- In Berkeley Journal of Sociology. -- Vol. XXXIV, 1989 (Box 118, Folder 70)
  - Articles re: Herbert Aptheker, 1989 (Box 118, Folder 71)
  - Lecture notes, 1989 (Box 118, Folder 72)
  - Flyers, 1989 (Box 118, Folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. U.S. colored troops sacrificed in blood for freedom?: book review of Joseph Glatthaars's Forged in a battle, 1990 Jan. 11 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Retire Dr. Strangelove, 1990 Jan. 31 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Book review of Michael W. Fitzgerald's The Union movement in the Deep South, 1990 Feb. 7 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Marxism: demise or renewal?: galley. -- Berkeley, Calif.: Marxist Library for Social Research, 1990 Mar. 30 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. A fitting biography of Rose Pastor Stokes: book review of Arthur Zipser and Pearl Zipser's Fire and grace: the life of Rose Pastor Stokes, 1990 Apr. 25 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Miscellaneous notes, 1990 July 27, an (1 l.) (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On affirmative action: notes for speech at Iowa State University, 1990 Oct. 11, ams (4 p.) + flyer (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The spiritual in Marxism: speech in Palo Alto, 1990 Dec. 11, tms (31 p.) + flyer (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - Articles re: Herbert Aptheker, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell, Charlene. Herbert Aptheker at 75 and the World at 2000 A.D.: text of address at Jewish Affairs annual dinner, 1990 Sept. 30 (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - Books of relevance for autobiography, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 12)
  - Notes, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 13)
  - The Aptheker advocate. -- Vol. 1, issue 1, [1990?] Aug. (Box 119, Folder 14)
  - National Lawyer's Guild convention: annotated agenda, 1990 May 31 - June 11 (Box 119, Folder 15)
  - Flyers, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 17)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Cease-fire, 1991 Jan. 17, ams (2 p.) (Box 119, Folder 18)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The mid-East crisis and the Jewish people. -- p. 4-5. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1991 Jan. (Box 119, Folder 19)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. 'The Civil war' - gripping but flawed history. -- p. 31-32. -- In Political Affairs, 1991 Feb. (Box 119, Folder 20)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The new world disorder: source, nature, cure. -- Berkeley, 1991 Apr. 12, ams (12 l.) (Box 119, Folder 21)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Eulogy for nephew Arthur, 1991 Apr. 12, tms (2 l.) (Box 119, Folder 22)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Bias in hiring. -- In People's Daily World, 1991 June 22 (Box 119, Folder 23)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Letter to the Editor, The Nation,, 1991 June 24, ams (2 p.) (Box 119, Folder 24)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Racism, anti-Semitism, and freedom of speech. -- In Thursday Night Forum; and In Jewish Affairs, 1991 July 12 (Box 119, Folder 25)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Police brutality, class and race. -- In People's World Weekly., 1991 July 27 (Box 119, Folder 26)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. How the Holocaust was planned and implemented, 1991 Aug. 10, clipping + an (Box 119, Folder 27)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Killing horse & workers, 1991 Aug. 24, 2 clippings + tms (2 p.) (Box 119, Folder 28)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Untitled manuscripts, 1991 Sept. 4, ams (3 p.) (Box 119, Folder 29)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Black nation. -- In The Nation, 1991 Sept. 23, p. 322 (Box 119, Folder 30)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. African-Americans and Jewish-Americans: common aspirants for the good life. -- p. 5-6. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1991 Sept. - Oct. / Nov. - Dec., tms (11 p.) + 1 clipping (Box 119, Folder 31)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Imprisonment & oppression. -- In People's Daily World, 1991 Nov. 9, clipping (Box 119, Folder 32)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Haiti and the struggle for abolition in the United States, 1991 Nov., tms + ams (Box 119, Folder 33)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Comments on 25th convention, CPUSA, 1991 Dec. 3, tms (2 p.) (Box 119, Folder 34)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Comments on 25th convention, CPUSA, Cleveland, Ohio, 1991 Dec. 3, ams (8 p.) (Box 119, Folder 35)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. History reclaims three left leaders. -- p. 16. -- In People's Weekly World, 1991 Dec. 7 (Box 119, Folder 36)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Remarks, S.F., 1991 Dec. 14, ams (6 p.) (Box 119, Folder 37)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. The mid-East crisis: what's to be done? -- p. 5-6. -- In Jewish Affairs, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 38)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Untitled, 1991, ams (5 p.) (Box 119, Folder 39)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Untitled manuscript fragment, 1991, tms (4 p.) with handwritten annotations (Box 119, Folder 40)
  - Book reviews by Aptheker, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 41)
  - Articles re: Aptheker, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 42)
  - Book reviews re: Aptheker, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 43)
  - Memoirs, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 44)
  - Flyers, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 45)
  - Notes, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 46)
  - Research materials, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 47)
  - Hostos course material, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 48)
  - U.C. Berkeley. Boalt Law School, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 49)
  - Communist Party of the U.S.A., XXV convention, 1991 (Box 119, Folder 50)
  - Communist Party of the U.S.A., XXV convention, Cleveland, 1991 Dec. 7 (Box 119, Folder 51)
  - Materials on Communist Party of the U.S.A., XXV convention, Cleveland, 1991 - 1992 (Box 119, Folder 52)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Notes for speech at Committees of Correspondence meeting, 1992 July 18, ams (4 p.) (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Speech in Berkeley on Haiti, 1992 Aug. 13, ams (5 p.) (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Book review on Wayne J. Urban's Black scholar: Horace Mann Bond, 1904-1972, 1992, tms (3 p.) (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Articles and letters by Herbert Aptheker, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois commemorative stamp ceremony invitation, 1992 Jan. 31 (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Freedman and Southern Society Project invitation, 1992 Dec. 29 (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - Flyers, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 9)
  - International Publishers book newsletter & full catalog, 1992 Fall - 1993 Spring (Box 120, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Affairs, 1992 Jan. / Feb. (Box 120, Folder 11)
  - Annual Black history / Black Liberation month calendar - Northeastern Univ., 1992 Feb. (Box 120, Folder 12)
  - Amistad Committee. Certification of purchase of a word in the inscription of the Memorial of Sengbe Pieh (Joseph Cinque), 1992 Mar. 25 (Box 120, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker inspires Boston activists. -- p. 15. -- In The Corresponder. -- Vol. 1, no. 2, 1992 Mar. - Apr. (Box 120, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 15)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Reflections on African American history. -- In The Corresponder. -- Vol. 2, no. 2, 1993 Feb. - Mar. (Box 120, Folder 16)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Free universal public education is necessary for democracy. -- In News for a People's World, 1993 Sept. (Box 120, Folder 17)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Wanted: a new deal. -- In Dialogue. -- No. 7, 1993 Fall / Winter, tms (5 p.) + clipping (Box 120, Folder 18)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Preface for Vol. VII of Documentary, 1993 Dec. 20 (Box 120, Folder 19)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. On Du Bois' move to Africa. -- In Monthly Review. -- Vol. 45, no. 7, 1993 Dec. (Box 120, Folder 20)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Black scholar: Horace Mann Bond, 1904-1972: review. -- In Science & Society. -- Vol. 57, no. 4, 1993 - 1994 Winter (Box 120, Folder 21)